<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on BS Techlog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on BS Techlog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.123.7</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 23:10:58 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Handling large document challenges for fine-tuning LLM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-10-27_llm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 23:10:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-10-27_llm/</guid>
      <description>In most LLM fine-tuning tutorials, they start with an available online dataset that you can easily use to play around with and fine-tune models. However, with real-world datasets, you might encounter tricky settings when handling large documents. Recently, I attended the Rutgers Health 2024 hackathon, where I had to deal with a document larger than an LLM&amp;rsquo;s context window size. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a solution back then, so our team chose a large-sized LLM with a larger context window.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Graph Representation Learning in Modern Computer Vision</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-07-25_gcn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 10:02:46 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-07-25_gcn/</guid>
      <description>Graph structures have been applied in many scientific fields, such as biology, computer science, and social network analysis. With the increasing popularity of machine learning, the graph representation learning (GRL) paradigm has emerged as effective methods. One example is the Graph Convolutional Network (GCN), which has shown remarkable success in tasks like node classification, graph generation and clustering by effectively capturing the complex relationships in graph data. GRL is also making big waves in modern computer vision.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low Rank Adaptation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-07-18_lora/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 04:05:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-07-18_lora/</guid>
      <description>Why Low Rank Adaptation Matters: A Closer Look at Its Impact on Machine Learning Low Rank Adaptation (LoRA) is a fine-tuning technique designed to efficiently update and adapt large pre-trained models, such as language or diffusion models, without retraining them entirely. Low Rank Adaptation was proposed in 2021 by Edward Hu et al. They demonstrated that LoRA significantly reduces the number of trainable parameters and GPU memory requirements. But how is that possible?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
